Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority (WMATA) Collection P016
DCPL Special Collections - MLK Library
Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority (WMATA) Collection
1971-1997
DCPL Special Collections - MLK Library
Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority
P016
1 Boxes
Arrangement
Processed without series.
Biographical / Historical
Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority (WMATA) was formed on November 6, 1966 when President Lyndon Johnson signed the bill creating the authority. Ground was broken on the construction of the first station, Judiciary Square, on December 9, 1969 with 4.2 mile Phase 1 opening to the public on March 27, 1976.
Custodial History
There is no deed of gift and it is uncertain as to how the library acquired these photographs. There is a handwritten note on the original housing, which indicates that they were a gift from WMATA, but no date or any other information could be found.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of 25 8"x10" and 5"x7" black and white photographic prints. The majority of the images illustrate the construction of various subway stations and tunnels throughout the city. A few images show finished stations and the operation of Metro train cars. One image shows a Metrobus.
Photographs; Transportation; Local transit; Subways
- Series 1
  - Union Station Station, 1973 November 11 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - MCI Arena Station, 1997 October 8 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - MCI Arena Station, 1996 April 22 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Union Station Station, 1973 July 5 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Farragut Square Station, 1971 November 8 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Fort Totten Station, 1991 September 27 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Georgia Avenue – Petworth Station, 1997 January 29 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Shady Grove Station (3 copies), 1987 April 28 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - L'Enfant Plaza construction, Ca. 1980 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Gallery Place Station, 1971 February (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Gallery Place Station, 1972 March 11 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Stadium Armory Station, Ca. 1980 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Anacostia Station, 1987 March 20 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Green Line Tunnel Work, 1985 May 9 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Tunnel Work, 1980 September 17 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Rhode Island Avenue Station, 1979 May 17 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Rhode Island Avenue Station (3 copies), 1980 May 7 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Train Operator, 1977 July 1 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Articulated Bus at Jefferson Memorial, 1983 August 26 (Box 1, Folder 19)